Guide to the Laura Dean Papers, 1966-2007
American Dance Festival Archives Durham, N.C., USA
Laura Dean papers 1966-2007
American Dance Festival Archives Box 90772 Durham, North Carolina, 27708-0772 USA Phone: 919-684-6402 Fax: 919-684-5459 Email: adfarchives@americandancefestival.org
Dean, Laura, 1945-
30.34 Linear Feet 5400 Items
Laura Dean (b. 1945) is an American choreographer and composer. In 1972, she established her company, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, where she created the choreography for forty works, and in most instances, created the music as well. A number of Dean's pieces were also accompanied by the music of Steve Reich. Dean continued to create works for her company until 2000. She received the Samuel H. Scripps/American Dance Festival Award for Lifetime Achievement in recognition of her accomplishments as a choreographer and composer in 2008.
Collection includes photographic prints, contact sheets, negatives, slides, clippings, programs, printed materials, posters, VHS videotapes, and an audiocassette.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Patrons must sign the Acknowledgement of Legal Responsibility and Privacy Rights form before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Access to videotapes or audiotapes in this collection requires the use of reference copies. To arrange for the creation of reference copies, if none exist, please contact American Dance Festival Archives.
Provenance
The Laura Dean Papers were received by the American Dance Festival Archives as a gift in May 2008.
Biographical Note
Laura Dean (b. 1945) is an American choreographer and composer. After her graduation from the High School of Performing Arts in New York, she became a member of the Paul Taylor Dance Company. In 1972, she established her own company, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, where she created the choreography for forty works, and in most instances, created the music as well. A number of Dean's pieces were also accompanied by the music of Steve Reich. She received commissions for new works from the American Dance Festival, the Kennedy Center, the Brooklyn Academy of Music, Het Muziektheater, Walker Art Center, Hansher Auditorium, the Hopkins Center, and the Avignon Festival. Dean was also commissioned to create works for the Royal Danish Ballet, the New York City Ballet, the Frankfurt Ballet, the Ohio Ballet, and the Joffrey Ballet. She created works for professional skating companies including the John Curry Skaters, the Next Ice Age, and the Ice Theater of New York. She created works for modern dance companies including the Bat-Dor Dance Company of Israel, the Concert Dance Company of Boston, Repertory Dance Theatre, and the Ririe-Woodbury Dance Company. Dean continued to create works for her own company until 2000. She received the Samuel H. Scripps/American Dance Festival Award for Lifetime Achievement in recognition of her accomplishments as a choreographer and composer in 2008.
Collection Overview
Collection includes photographic prints, contact sheets, negatives, slides, clippings, programs, printed materials, posters, VHS videotapes, and an audiocassette.
Collection Arrangement
The majority of the photographic and printed materials was arranged in 49 binders by Laura Dean. These materials were grouped as to whether they were created for Dean's company, other companies, or for students. Within these sub-series, materials were then most often arranged by choreographic work, and then arranged chronologically by the date of composition of the work (i.e., most materials related to a work are filed under the year of the work's creation, irregardless of when the materials were created.) Interspersed within this chronological arrangement are materials related to specific performance engagements or tours.
Following the binders are four books of over-sized photographic prints, arranged chronologically, two boxes of posters, and seven boxes of VHS videotapes of performances, also grouped by whether they were created for Dean's company, other companies, or for students.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Dean, Laura, 1945-
Reich, Steve, 1936-
Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians
Choreographers -- United States
Modern Dance -- United States
Contents of Collection
- Photographs and Printed Materials, 1966-2007, 10 Boxes
  Includes photographic prints, contact sheets, negatives, slides, clippings, programs, press releases, and other printed materials.
  - Laura Dean Companies Works and Tours, 1966-2000
    - Binder 1, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
      - Farewell, 1968
      - Bach Preludes, 1971
      - A Dance Concert, 1971
      - Yoga Breathing and Dance 1971
    - Binder 2, 1972
      - Trio, 1972
      - Quartet Squared, 1972
      - Stamping Dance, 1972-1973
      - European Tour with Steve Reich and Musicians, 1972
    - Binder 3, 1972
      - Circle Dance, 1972-1973
    - Binder 4, 1973
      - NYU Performances with Steve Reich and Musicians, 1973
        - Walking Dance
        - Jumping Dance
        - Circle Dance
        - Square Dance
      - Changing Pattern Steady Pulse, 1973
    - Binder 5, 1974
      - Spinning Dance, 1974
      - Response Dance, 1974
      - Changing, 1974
    - Binder 6, 1975 (Box 2)
      - 7 Dances By Laura Dean and Company in The Drama Review, March 1975
      - Drumming, 1975
      - Laura Dean portraits, 1975
    - Binder 7, 1976
      - Solo for Voice and Piano, 1976
      - Song, 1976, 1978
    - Binder 8, 1976
      - Song, 1976
      - Dance, 1976, 1978, 1989
    - Binder 9, 1977
      - Geometries: The Song and Dance of Laura Dean in Dance Magazine, November 1977
      - Song, 1977
      - Dance, 1977
      - Student Workshops, Arconsanti, Arizona, 1977
      - Spiral, 1977
    - Binder 10, 1978
      - Laura Dean portraits, 1978
      - Entermedia Theatre Performances, 1978
        - Song
        - Dance
      - Walnut Street Theatre Performances, 1978
        - Song
        - Dance
      - Spiral, 1978
    - Binder 11, 1979 (Box 3)
      - Laura Dean portraits, 1979
      - Phrases/Spinning, 1979
      - Music, 1979
      - Company portrait, 1979
    - Binder 12, 1979
      - Music, 1979
      - Moving Pictures: A Dance Photography Portfolio featuring Laura Dean in Performing Arts Journal
      - Pattern, 1979
      - Dance, 1979
    - Binder 13, 1980
      - Laura Dean portraits, 1980
      - Pattern, 1980
      - Dance, 1980
      - Music, 1980
      - Pattern II, 1980
      - Tympani, 1980
    - Binder 14, 1981
      - Capezio advertisement featuring Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians
      - Spin and Pulse in Horizon, January 1981
      - Tympani, 1981
      - Song, 1981
      - Pattern III, 1981
      - US International Communication Agency Tour: Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians in India, 1981
    - Binder 15, 1981
      - US International Communication Agency Tour: Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians in India, New Zealand, and Indonesia, 1981
      - Dancer Laura Dean in SPAN, May 1981
    - Binder 16, 1981 (Box 4)
      - Tours, 1981
        - Song
        - Tympani
        - Dance
        - Pattern III
        - Night
        - Laura Dean Lectures
    - Binder 17, 1982
      - Tours, 1982
        - Tympani
        - Dance
        - Night
      - Sky Light, 1982
      - Solo in Red, 1982
    - Binder 18, 1982
      - Sky Light, 1982
      - Tours, 1982
    - Binder 19, 1983
      - Enochian, 1983
      - Inner Circle, 1983
      - Tours, 1983
    - Binder 20, 1984
      - Laura Dean portraits, 1984
      - Trio, 1984
      - American Dance Festival Tokyo, 1984
      - Tours, 1984
        - Inner Circle
        - Sky Light
        - Trio
    - Binder 21, 1985 (Box 5)
      - Transformer, 1985
      - Impact, 1985
    - Binder 22, 1985
      - Transformer, 1985
      - Impact, 1985
      - Company portrait, 1985
      - Transformer, 1985
      - Sky Light, 1985
      - Laura Dean Lecture at NYU, 1985
    - Binder 23, 1986
      - Laura Dean portraits, 1986
      - Company portraits, 1986
      - Tours, 1986
        - Sky Light
        - Impact
        - Transformer
      - Magnetic, 1986
    - Binder 24, 1986
      - U.S. Tours, 1986
        - Sky Light
        - Impact
        - Transformer
        - Magnetic
        - Tympani
    - Binder 25, 1987
      - U.S. and European Tours, 1987
        - Magnetic
        - Tympani
        - Sky Light
        - Impact
      - Shaman, 1987
    - Binder 26, 1987 (Box 6)
      - Laura Dean Interview in Upstart, 1987
      - Dancing for Life AIDS Benefit, 1987
    - Binder 27, 1988
      - Equator, 1988
      - U.S. and European Tours, 1988
      - Laura Dean Musicians Concert, 1988
    - Binder 28, 1988
      - U.S. Tours, 1988
      - Madrid Tour, 1988
    - Binder 29, 1989
      - U.S. Tours, 1989
        - Magnetic
        - Tympani
        - Dance
        - Equator
        - Sky Light
      - Memory, 1989
    - Binder 30, 1990
      - U.S. Tours, 1990
      - Shaman II, 1990
      - University of New Hampshire Residence, 1990
      - Infinity, 1990
    - Binder 31, 1991 (Box 7)
      - U.S. and Portugal Tours, 1991
        - Equator
        - Tympani
        - Magnetic
        - Inner Circle
        - Infinity
    - Binder 32, 1992-1997
      - Ecstasy, 1993 (original title War)
      - Tours, 1992-1997
    - Binder 33, 1997-2007
      - Trilogy, 1999
        - Sphere, 1997
        - Solar Wind, 1998
        - Celestial Navigation, 1999
      - View Over Atlantis, 2000
      - Sky Light reconstruction by Roger Belman, 2007
  - Ballets and Other Companies, 1980-2007
    - Binder 34, 1980-1982 (Box 7)
      - Night premiere, the Joffrey Ballet, 1980
      - Fire premiere, the Joffrey Ballet, 1982
      - David Bowie's Fashion video featuring choreography by Laura Dean, 1981
    - Binder 35, 1983-1984
      - Fire, the Joffrey Ballet, 1982-1983
      - Burn, John Curry Skating Company, 1983-1985
      - Tehillim/Psalms, Bat-Dor-Dance Company, 1984-1985
    - Binder 36, 1985 (Box 8)
      - Patterns of Change, the Ohio Ballet, 1985-1986
      - Night, the Joffrey Ballet, 1985
    - Binder 37, 1986
      - Force Field, the Joffrey Ballet, 1986
    - Binder 38, 1986
      - Force Field, the Joffrey Ballet, 1986-1988
    - Binder 39, 1987
      - Gravity, the Ohio Ballet, 1987
      - For Two, the Ohio Ballet, 1987
      - Force Field, the Joffrey Ballet, 1987
    - Binder 40, 1988
      - Dream Collector, Concert Dance Company of Boston, 1988
      - Gravity, the Ohio Ballet, 1988
      - Space, New York City Ballet, 1988-1992
    - Binder 41, 1989
      - Fire, reconstruction by Frankfurt Ballet, 1989
      - Laura Dean's Myth and Ritual in the Age of Relativity lecture, 1989
      - Arrow of Time, Berkshire Ballet, 1989
      - Ocean, the Next Ice Age, 1989
      - Space, New York City Ballet, 1989
      - Pearls and Tears music video for Andreas Vollenweider's album Dancing with the Lion, 1989
    - Binder 42, 1990 (Box 9)
      - Delta, Royal Danish Ballet, 1990
      - Quantum, the Ohio Ballet, 1990-1991
    - Binder 43, 1991-1993
      - Sky Light, reconstructed by Errol Simpson, Repertory Dance Theatre, Salt Lake City, Utah, 1991
      - Sedona Sunrise, Ice Theater of New York, 1991
      - Structure, the Joffrey Ballet, 1992
      - Light Field, the Joffrey Ballet, 1992
      - Light, AMAN International Music and Dance Company, 1993-1994
    - Binder 44, 1993-1994
      - Sometimes it Snows in April (Part I of Billboards), the Joffrey Ballet, 1993-1994
      - Earth, the Ohio Ballet, 1993-1999
      - Nightwind, Albany Berkshire Ballet, 1993
      - Tenmile, Ririe-Woodbury Dance Company, 1994
      - Cloud, the Royal Danish Ballet, 1994
    - Binder 45, 1995-2007
      - You Don't Bring Me Flowers Anymore, the Joffrey Ballet, 1996
      - Ni Bthaska Ke, Ballet Omaha, 1995
      - Niagara, Pick of the Crop Dance Company, 1995
      - New Dance/the Gift, American Indian Dance Theatre, 1998-2004
      - Creative Force, the Joffrey Ballet, 1999-2004
      - Astral Journey, the Atlanta Ballet, 2001
      - View Over Atlantis, reconstructed by Jennifer Sommers, Meredith Dance Theatre, 2003-2004
      - View Over Atlantis, reconstructed by Jill Greeson (2000) and Paula Weber (2004), Wylliams Henry Danse Theatre
  - Student and Workshop Works, 1975-2001
    - Binder 46 (Box 9)
      - God Are in a Plain Field (Let's Talk Value), Goddard College Theatre, 1975
      - Line and Circle, Pratt Institute, 1974-1975
      - Songdance, The American University, 1976
      - Line and Circle, Walken Art Center, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1978
      - Mountain Song, Utah Repertory Dance Theatre Summer Program, 1978
      - The Oberlin Pieces, Oberlin College, 1979
      - Changes (a work for Chicago), MoMing, Chicago, 1979
      - Lines, The Holland Festival, Amsterdam, 1979
      - Spinning Workshop, The American Dance Festival, 1979
      - Residency in Auvignon, France, 1981
      - Music and Dance, California State University, Humboldt, 1988
      - Student Work at Southern Methodist University, 1992
      - Dance for Eight Women, Columbia College, 1993
      - Breath of Fire, California State University, Long Beach, 1994
      - Tao, Raleigh Dance Theatre, 2002
      - Astral Flight, Duke University, 2001
  - Book and Article Excerpts
    - Binder 47 (Box 10)
      Book and article excerpts.
  - Awards and Art Exhibits
    - Binder 48
      Awards, honors, grants, exhibits.
  - Lists
    - Binder 49
      List of works created by Laura Dean (does not include student works) and teaching list.
- Over-Sized Photographic Prints, 1971-1990, 2 Boxes
  - Book 1, 1971-1976 (Box 11)
    Laura Dean portraits, Steve Reich, early company photos, Stamping Dance, Drumming, Song, Spinning Dance, Quartet Squared, Phase Patterns.
  - Book 2, 1974-1993
    Tympani, Song, Ecstasy, Spinning Dance, Drumming, Magnetic, Sky Light, India tour, Laura Dean dance workshop in India, Laura Dean Musicians in rehearsal.
  - Book 3, 1971-1993 (Box 12)
    Peter Gabriel tour, Laura Dean portraits, Fire, Force Field, Light Field, Night (the Joffrey Ballet).
  - Book 4, 1988-1990
    Space (New York City Ballet), Delta (the Royal Danish Ballet).
- Posters, 1975-1994 and undated, 2 Boxes
  - Fire, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, artwork courtesy Michael Graves, signed by Laura Dean and Michael Graves. (Box 13)
  - Drumming, Laura Dean and Dance Company, Steve Reich and Musicians, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Apr. 3-6, 1975.
  - Song, Laura Dean Dance Company, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Lepercq Space, Apr. 29-May 2.
  - Spiral, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Nov. 11-13.
  - Equator, Magnetic, Impact, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Muziek Theater, Feb. 25, 26, 28.
  - The Next Wave: New Masters at the Brooklyn Academy of Music, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Oct. 30-Nov. 1.
  - Dance at Orchestra Hall: Premiere of Song (Apr. 8, 1976), Duet (with David White, Apr. 12, 1976), Laura Dean and Dance Company, The Walker Art Center, Apr., 1976.
  - Stamping Dance, Circle Dance, Changing Patterns, Steady Pulse, Jumping Dance, Laura Dean and Dance Company, Eisner-Lubin Auditorium, Loeb Auditorium, New York University, Dec. 8, Dec. 14.
  - On the Boards Presents: Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Meany Hall, Seattle, Mar. 31-Apr. 2.
  - Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Orchestra Hall, Walker Art Center, Minneapolis, MN, Oct. 27.
  - Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Kamanhi Auditorium, New Delhi, May 15-16, 1981.
  - Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Presented at the Theater Terbuka, Jakarta, Indonesia, by the International Communication agency, May 9, 1981.
  - Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Choreographie and Musik, Laura Dean, Alte Oper (Old Opera), Frankfurt, Germany, May 29-30.
  - Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Presented at the Maidment Theater in Auckland, New Zealand, by the International Communication Agency, Apr. 23-26.
  - Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Presented in Ljubljana, Yugoslavia, by the United States Information Service, July 6, 1983.
  - ADF Tokyo, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, 1984.
  - An American Classic, The Joffrey Ballet, The Wiltern Theatre, May 8-June 7 1992.
  - NY Ballet AF Laura Dean, Det Kongelige Theater, 1993-1994.
  - Inner Circle, 14th International Festival Sofia Music Weeks, Bulgaria. (Box 14)
  - Cloud, Royal Danish Ballet.
  - Delta, Royal Danish Ballet.
- Video, 1973-2001, 7 Boxes
  All video in this collection is NTSC VHS unless otherwise noted. Access to the original VHS videotapes is restricted. Any use of video requires the use of reference copies. To arrange for the creation of reference copies, if none exist, please contact American Dance Festival Archives.
  - Laura Dean Companies Works and Tours, 1973-2000
    - Square Dance, Phase Patterns, Laura Dean with Steve Reich, NYU Loeb, Apr. 1973 (Box 15)
    - Walking Dance, Square Dance, Jumping Dance, Laura Dean, Apr. 4, 1973
    - Walking Dance, Clapping Music, Square Dance, Phase Patterns, Laura Dean and Dancers, Steve Reich and Musicians, NYU, Apr. 1973
    - Circle Dance, Laura Dean, NYU Loeb/Eisner Auditorium, Apr. 1973
    - Circle Dance, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, NYU Loeb/Eisner Auditorium, Apr. 1973
    - Jumping Dance, Laura Dean, NYU Loeb Apr. 1973
    - Walking Dance, Jumping Dance (partial), Laura Dean and Dance Company, Steve Reich and Musicians, Apr. 28, 1973
    - Changing Pattern, Steady Pulse, Laura Dean and Dance Company, NYU Loeb/Eisner Auditorium, Dec. 1973 (2 copies)
    - Drumming Part I, Laura Dean and Dance Company, Steve Reich and Musicians, BAM, Apr. 1975
    - Drumming Part II, Laura Dean, BAM, Apr. 1975
    - Dance, Laura Dean, Minneapolis, 1979
    - Song, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Walnut St. Theater, PA, Nov. 18, 1978
    - Song, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Walnut St. Theater, Philadelphia, PA, Nov. 1978
    - Song, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Orchestra Hall, Minneapolis, Oct. 8, 1978
    - Spiral, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Walker Art Center Auspices, Orchestra Hall, Apr. 1978
    - Spiral, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians (3 copies)
    - Music, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 12, 1979
    - Music, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 12, 1979 (2 copies) (Box 16)
    - Inner Circle, Enochian, Sky Light, Laura Dean, American Tour, Riverside, CA, Oct. 1983
    - Inner Circle, Laura Dean (2 copies)
    - Inner Circle, Enochian, Sky Light, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, NYU Showing, June 1983
    - Inner Circle, Enochian, Sky Light, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Riverside, CA, 1983
    - Sky Light, Transformer, Impact, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Brooklyn Academy of Music, Next Wave Festival, Fall 1985 (4 copies)
    - Tympani, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, PBS Television, 1981 (2 copies)
    - Sky Light, Tympani, Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 1986 (4 copies)
    - Sky Light, Tympani, Magnetic, Laura Dean
    - Tympani, Transformer, Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 10, 1986 (2 copies)
    - Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 10, 1986
    - Convergence (Brandeis awards show with score and stills from Tympani), 1986
    - Sky Light, Tympani, Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Joyce, 1987 (4 copies)
    - Sky Light, Tympani, Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Joyce, Apr. 10, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Sky Light, Tympani, Magnetic, 1987
    - Sky Light, Tympani, Magnetic, Apr. 10, 1987
    - Shaman, Inner Circle, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians
    - Tympani, Shaman, Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, June 20, 1987
    - Equator, Magnetic, Impact, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Het Muziektheater, Amsterdam, Feb. 26, 1988
    - Tympani, Transformer, Magnetic, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 10, 1986
    - Magnetic, Memory, Equator, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, UCLA Royce Hall, Apr. 1, 1989 (2 copies)
    - Magnetic, Memory, Equator, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Zellerbach Hall, Apr. 7, 1989
    - Magnetic, Memory, Equator, Laura Dean Dancers, UCB Zellerbach Hall, Apr. 8, 1989
    - Equator, Shaman II, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers (5 copies)
    - Sacred Dances, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers (6 copies) (Box 18)
    - Inner Circle, Sacred Dances, Infinity, Laura Dean, Northeastern University, Boston, MA, Apr. 19, 1991
      A DVD reference copy is available for viewing and is located in box 22.
      A Beta SP submaster copy is located in box 23.
    - Infinity, Sacred Dances, Laura Dean, Northeastern University, Boston, MA, Apr. 20, 1991
    - Sky Light, Infinity, Ecstasy, Laura Dean, ADF, June, 1993
    - Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, ADF, 1993
    - Sky Light, Infinity, Ecstasy, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, ADF, June 17, 1993
    - Music, Night, Magnetic, Shaman II, Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program C #1, May 3, 1990
    - Music, Night, Magnetic, Shaman II, Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program C #2, May 6, 1990
    - Sky Light, Inner Circle, Equator, Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program B #2, May 5, 1990
    - Night, Dance, Spiral, Tympani, Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program A #2, May 2, 1990
    - Night, Dance, Spiral, Tympani, Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program A, May 1, 1990
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, Program A, Shoot 1, Parts 1 and 2, May 1, 1990 (2 tapes)
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program A, Shoot 2, May 2, 1990
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program B, Shoot 1, May 4, 1990
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program B, Shoot 2, May 5, 1990
    - Sky Light, Inner Circle, Equator, Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program B #1, May 4, 1990
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program C, Shoot 1, May 3, 1990
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, NYC, Program C, Shoot 2, May 6, 1990
    - Infinity, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July, 1990
    - Infinity, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 1990 (Box 19)
    - Infinity, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 12, 1990
    - Equator, Shaman II, Infinity, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, ADF, July 12, 1990
    - Laura Dean Performance, ADF, July 12, 1990
    - Magnetic, Inner Circle, Infinity, Laura Dean Dancers and Musicians, Hartford, CT, Austin Arts Center, Trinity College, Jan. 26, 1991
    - Skylight, Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, Joyce Theatre, Apr. 28, 1994 (full stage)
    - Skylight, Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, Joyce Theatre, May 1, 1994 (fixed camera)
    - Skylight, Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, Joyce Theatre, Apr. 27, 1994 (hand held)
    - Skylight, Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, Joyce Theatre, Apr., 30, 1994
    - Laura Dean, Joyce Theatre, May 1, 1994 (matinee)
    - Skylight, Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, Joyce Theatre, Apr. 28, 1994 (full stage)
    - Skylight, Ecstasy, Infinity, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, Joyce Theatre, Apr. 29, 1994 (full stage)
    - Laura Dean, Apr. 29, 1994 (hand held)
    - Equator, Tympani, Infinity, Laura Dean, Stanford University, Jan. 22, 1991
    - Sphere, Laura Dean, 1998
    - Sphere, Solar Wind, Laura Dean Musicians and Dancers, 1998
    - Trilogy: Sphere, Solar Wind, Celestial Navigation, 1999 (2 copies)
    - View Over Atlantis, Laura Dean, NC Dance Festival, Jan. 2000
  - Ballets and Other Companies, 1985-1999
    - Patterns of Change, Laura Dean, Ohio Ballet, Feb. 15, 1985 (Box 19)
    - Gravity, For Two, Gravity, Laura Dean, Ohio Ballet, Feb. 13-14, 1987 (Box 20)
    - Quantum, Laura Dean, Ohio Ballet, 1990